A Guide to the Papers of Homer Stille Cummings, ca.1850-1955
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- SERIES III: CORRESPONDENCE OF THE ATTORNEY GENERAL AND POST-ATTORNEY GENERAL, 1933-1956
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Lincoln Memorial University 1935 May-1956 July, 3 folders (Box 123)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Charles E. Lindberg, Jr. kidnapping case, and others involving inter-state travel 1933 August-1936 April (Box 124)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Edwin L. Lindell, Minnesota Law and Order League 1936 May-June (Box 124)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Samuel W. Liske 1937 February (Box 124)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Litchfield Law School 1928 April-1937 November (Box 124)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Norman M. Littell, Assistant Attorney General 1939 June-1950 (Box 124)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Charles D. Lockwood 1933 March-1955, 3 folders (Box 124)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Scott M. Loftin, Senator from Florida 1935 February-1953 December (Box 125)
  - Attorney General Personal File - M.M.Logan, Senator from Kentucky 1936 August-1939 October (Box 125)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Augustine Lonergan, Senator from Connecticut 1934 September-1947 October (Box 125)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Protests against Senator Lonergan, his struggle for renomination 1938 June-September (Box 125)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Breckinridge Long 1933 June-1946 May (Box 125)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Loophold Legislation, re: tax matters 1937 July-August (Box 125)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Louisiana Cases (income taxes) 1935 August-1937 February (Box 125)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Louisiana Income Tax Cases, when the question was brought up again in 1940 1940 January (Box 125)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Louisiana situation (re: Martial Law, protection of Republican Form of Government) 1934 January-1936 June (Box 125)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Louisville Clearance (memoranda re: Eminent Domain) 1936 February (Box 125)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Malcolm R. Lovell, secretary, Quaker Service Council 1940 May-1951 October (Box 125)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Lower California and Norther Mexico (maps) n.d. (Box 125)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Lynching, Anti-Lynching Bills 1935 February-1937 April (Box 125)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Lynn (Mass.) Bridge, NIRA project 1933 July-September (Box 125)
  - Attorney General Personal File - General "McC-Maci" 1933 December-1956 July, 2 folders (Box 125)
  - Attorney General Personal File - General "Mack-Moo" 1933 December-1956 July, 6 folders (Box 126)
  - Attorney General Personal File - General "Mor-Mus" 1933 December-1956 July, 2 folders (Box 127)
  - Attorney General Personal File - William Gibbs McAdoo 1934 July-1941 February (Box 127)
  - Attorney General Personal File - J. Harvey McCarthy 1933 March-1935 (Box 127)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - John T. McCarthy 1940 January-1954 December (Box 127)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Charles P. McClelland 1935 February-1939 January (Box 127)
  - Attorney General Personal File - John E. McClure 1938 June-1950 May (Box 127)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - William Wallace McCallum 1945 August (Box 127)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Judge Leon McCord 1936 dec-1938 June (Box 127)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Thomas J. McDermott 1937 May-1938 October (Box 127)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Frank P. McEvoy 1933 March-1945 June (Box 127)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Carl McFarland 1934 May-1956 July (Box 127)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Carl McFarland 1934 October-1956 July, 2 folders (Box 128)
  - Memoranda from Homer Stille Cummings to Carl McFarland, with newsclippings mainly re: the Supreme Court 1939-1947 (Box 128)
  - Attorney General Personal File - James L. McGovern 1933 April-1951 March (Box 128)
  - Attorney General Personal File - James P. McGranery 1952 May-June (Box 128)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings re: J. Howard McGrath 1941 January-1954 April (Box 128)
  - Attorney General Personal File - William McGraw 1937 January-1938 July (Box 128)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Matthew F. McGuire 1937 March-1947 May (Box 128)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Vale H. McGuire 1935 August-1942 May (Box 128)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Marvin H. McIntyre 1934 January-1941 April (Box 128)
  - Attorney General Personal File - John E. Mack 1933 March-1952 May (Box 128)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Senator Kenneth McKellar 1934 May-1955 June (Box 128)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Ben McKinney 1936 April-1954 February (Box 128)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Angus D. McLean 1934 October-1938 June (Box 128)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Mrs. Evalyn McLean 1936 December-1944 November (Box 129)
  - Attorney General Personal File - James N. McLean 1936 February (Box 129)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Brien McMahon 1935-1945, 8 folders (Box 129)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Brien McMahon 1946 January-1952 June, 4 folders (Box 130)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Brien McMahon and materials on McMahon's death 1952 July-December (Box 130)
  - Correspondence & Papers relating to the late Senator Brien McMahon 1953-1959 (Box 130)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Congressman Thomas S. McMillan 1936 November-1938 October (Box 131)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Charles L. McNary 1935 August-1940 July (Box 131)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Archibald McNeil 1933 March-1939 January, 2 folders (Box 131)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Paul V. McNutt 1938 March-1942 April (Box 131)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Samuel S. McReynolds 1933 June-1939 July (Box 131)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Congressman John J. McSwain 1936 January-August (Box 131)
  - Attorney General Personal File - J. Walter Madigan 1933 June-1956 July (Box 131)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Walter N. Maguire 1933 March-1944 December (Box 131)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Mail Interference Cases 1937 July-August (Box 131)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Mailing Lists 1930 June-1937 February (Box 131)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Francis T. Maloney 1933 March-1944 December (Box 131)
  - Attorney General Personal File - George F. Mara 1934 March (Box 131)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Charles H. Marca 1935 July-1945 May (Box 131)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Maritime Commission 1936 October-November (Box 131)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Mark Twain Society 1937 February-1946 September (Box 131)
  - Attorney General Personal File - John Marshall 1936 January-1939 December (Box 131)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings re: Thomas R. Marshall 1916 May-1919 December (Box 131)
  - Attorney General Personal File - L.R. Martineau 1935 July-1943 December (Box 132)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Guy Mason 1941 July-1955 August (Box 132)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Masonic Lodge (Hiram, New Haven) 1935 January-1938 January (Box 132)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Lillie Thompson Mather 1938 July-1942 February (Box 132)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Charles Mattson - Kidnapped 1937 January (Box 132)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Herbert A. May 1945 November-1955 January (Box 132)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Mead & Tierney Tracts 1933 July-1949 June (Box 132)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Gaston Means 1936 July-August (Box 132)
  - Attorney General Personal File - A.W. Mellon (Protests & Communications) 1934 May-1937 December (Box 132)
  - Memoranda of Homer Stille Cummings 1944-1956 (Box 132)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Mercantile Strike 1936 November (Box 132)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Willis H. Meredith 1937 October-1942 July (Box 132)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Schuyler Merritt 1933 March-1953 April (Box 132)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Eugene Meyer 1936 January-1946 June (Box 132)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Mid-Pines Tournament 1955 May-1956 April (Box 132)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Mid-Transcontinental Route 1930 August-1938 (Box 132)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Vincent M. Miles 1933 July-1947 August (Box 132)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Milford Fisheries Laboratory 1938 June-September (Box 133)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Military Power of President 1934 July-1937 March (Box 133)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Milk 1938 July-October (Box 133)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Justin Miller 1936 August-1954 August (Box 133)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Robert J. Miller 1937 March-1942 April (Box 133)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Maurice M. Milligan 1936 August-1945 September (Box 133)
  - Attorney General Personal File - George Fort Milton 1933 March-1944 September (Box 133)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Milwaukee Journal1936 July (Box 133)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Minimum Wage 1937 March-April (Box 133)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Senator Sherman Minton 1935 August-1952 December (Box 133)
  - Attorney General Personal File - William D. Mitchell 1937 April-1955 September (Box 133)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Raymond E. Moley 1934 March-1936 July (Box 133)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Monopolies and the Courts1938 January (Box 133)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Monopoly Investigation 1938 July (Box 133)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Montana Power Company 1937 May (Box 133)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Montevideo Foreclosure Cases 1936 July-August (Box 133)
  - Attorney General Personal File - John F. Montgomery (U.S. Legation - Budapest) 1933 March-1945 December (Box 133)
  - Attorney General Personal File - John F. Montgomery 1933 March-1953 April (Box 134)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Tom Mooney 1934 May-1938 May (Box 134)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Charles E. Moore 1933 October-1946 October (Box 134)
  - Attorney General Personal File - R. Walton Moore 1935 June-1937 May (Box 134)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - William Morgan 1952 (Box 134)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Henry W. Morganthau, Jr. 1934 January-1940 January (Box 134)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Arthur A. Morris, M.D. 1952 (Box 134)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Ambassador Dave H. Morris 1935 August-1937 January (Box 134)
  - Attorney General Personal File - George H. Morris 1936 September-1954 December (Box 134)
  - Attorney General Personal File - James W. Morris 1935 January-1956 August (Box 134)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Mortgage 1934 November (Box 134)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Moscow Fire Insurance Company 1936 September (Box 134)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Moths 1936 August (Box 134)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Arthur Muller 1935 August-1938 July (Box 134)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Edward Muller 1943 March-1948 September (Box 134)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Miss Amy Murphy 1940 December-1947 July (Box 134)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Frances P. Murphy 1940 October-1943 March (Box 135)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Frank Murphy 1933 April-1951 February (Box 135)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Mayor John Murphy 1937 November-1944 August (Box 135)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - General "Na-No" 1933 March-1956 July, 2 folders (Box 135)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Edward J. Nalley 1934 February-May (Box 135)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Aluizio Napoleao 1946 September (Box 135)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Narcotics Cases, NYC 1938 September-October (Box 135)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Nashville Bank 1935 February (Box 135)
  - Attorney General Personal File - NAACP 1936 December (Box 135)
  - Attorney General Personal File - National Democratic Club 1939 Marcy-1956 July (Box 136)
  - Attorney General Personal File - National Gallery of Art 1936 December-1937 March (Box 135)
  - Attorney General Personal File - National Geographical Society 1930 October-1935 January (Box 135)
  - Attorney General Personal File - National Guarantee Title Company 1936 December (Box 135)
  - Attorney General Personal File - National Industrial Recovery Act 1935 May (Box 135)
  - Attorney General Personal File - National Labor Relations Board 1934 December-1938 (Box 136)
  - Attorney General Personal File - National Metropolitan Bank 1935 December-1956 May (Box 136)
  - Attorney General Personal File - National Police Academy n.d. (Box 136)
  - Attorney General Personal File - National Recovery Administration 1935 October-November (Box 136)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings re: Navy Day Dinner 1942 June-October (Box 136)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Navy Day Dinner 1942 October & 1945 October, 2 folders (Box 136)
  - Attorney General Personal File - District Council of the Navy League of the United States 1943 July-1951 December (Box 136)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Nazi Matters 1938 August-November (Box 136)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Colonel William H. Neblett 1936 September-1937 (Box 136)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Matthew Neely 1935 August-1954 November (Box 136)
  - Attorney General Personal File - New Buildings 1938 July-September (Box 136)
  - Attorney General Personal File - New York, New Haven and Hartford Railroad Company 1916 January-1944 August (Box 136)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings re: New York University School of Law 1948 April-May (Box 136)
  - Attorney General Personal File - New York World's Fair 1937 May-August (Box 136)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Hobart Newman 1937 July-August (Box 136)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Oliver P. Newman 1948 January-1956 April (Box 136)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings re: edwin L. Newmarker 1945 September-1946 July (Box 137)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Newspaper Reception (24 October 1934) 1934 October-November (Box 137)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Newspaper Reception (20 June 1937) 1936 January-1937 June (Box 137)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Newspapers 1954 January-November (Box 137)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Nine Foot Channel 1936 February-December (Box 137)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings re: Governor James Noe 1941 March (Box 137)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings re: Mark Norman 1946 March-May (Box 137)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Senator George W. Norris 1935 January-1937 April (Box 137)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Northeastern Penitentiary 1936 July (Box 137)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Northern Pacific Case 1937 July-1938 April (Box 137)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Norwalk Post Office 1933 March-1936 February (Box 137)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Norwalk Post Office Protests 1935 August-1936 February (Box 137)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - General "O" 1934 February-1956 August (Box 138)
  - Attorney General Personal File - John Lord O'Brian 1935 January-1936 January (Box 138)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Mary M. O'Brien 1938 October-1940 August (Box 1378)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Patrick H. O'Brien 1934 August-1937 July (Box 138)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Cardinal William O'Connell 1934 November-1935 April (Box 138)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Basil O'Connor 1933 August-1953 February (Box 138)
  - Attorney General Personal File - J.F.T. O'Connor (comptroller of the currency) 1934 May-1945 November (Box 138)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Congressman John J. O'Connor 1936 November-1939 January (Box 138)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings re: Officer Training Schools 1951 February-March (Box 138)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Charlton Ogburn (consul for AFL) 1935 November-1940 January (Box 138)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Oil Cases (Standard Oil of Indiana) 1936 August-1938 August (Box 138)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Herman Oliphant 1935 August-December (Box 138)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Webster J. Oliver 1938 May-1940 June (Box 138)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Culbert L. Olson 1936 June-1937 February (Box 138)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Senator Joseph C. O'Mahoney 1933 November-1954 November (Box 138)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Omicron Delta Kappa - University of Pittsburgh (John Bracken) 1933 October-1938 November (Box 138)
  - Correspondence & Opinions of Homer Stille Cummings 1935 November (Box 139)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Organization of American States 1954 November-December (Box 139)
  - Attorney General Personal File - John A. Orr 1934 November-1943 (Box 139)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings re: Sergio Osmina (Box 139)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Fulton Oursler 1934 October-1953 October (Box 139)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings re: Overseas National Airways 1951 June-1955 July (Box 139)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Robert L. Owen 1936 April-November (Box 139)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Caroline H. Owings 1932 January-1941 December, 2 folders (Box 139)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Alvin M. Owsley 1933 June-1936 July (Box 139)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - General "Pag-Pas" 1934 March-1956 August (Box 139)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - General "Pat-Py" 1934 March-1956 August (Box 140)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Frank Pace 1933 April-1950 May (Box 140)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Pacific Coast Standard Oil 1937 June (Box 140)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Joseph A. Padway 1937 December-1938 March (Box 140)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings re: Palm Beach, Florida 1953 July-1956 June (Box 140)
  - Attorney General Personal File - A. Mitchell Palmer 1935 June-1936 September (Box 140)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Panama Canal Tolls 1936 January (Box 140)
  - Attorney General Personal File - William J. Pape 1933 December-1934 October (Box 141)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Brig. General F. LeJ. Parker 1933 February-August (Box 141)
  - Attorney General Personal File - John J. Parker 1935 May-1954 October (Box 141)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Edward Parlato 1940 March-1946 March (Box 141)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Parlton-Smith Case 1935 February (Box 141)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Parole Information re: Release on 1936 March-May (Box 141)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Parole System 1935 February-1936 January (Box 141)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Frank M. Parrish 1937 October-1938 November (Box 141)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Party for J.D. Officers 1937 June (Box 141)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Passports 1935 August-1937 October (Box 141)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Congressman Wright Patman 1937 September-1954 November (Box 141)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Patriotic Society of Peru 1937 October-1939 June (Box 141)
  - Attorney General Personal File - William R. Pattangall 1933 March-1934 March (Box 141)
  - Attorney General Personal File - William J. Pearson 1933 March-1938 January (Box 141)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Westbrook Pegler 1937 February-1955 January (Box 141)
  - Attorney General Personal File - John Pelenyi (Hungarian Minister) 1938 April-1940 April (Box 141)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Frances Perkins 1937 December-1945 July (Box 141)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Phi Alpha Delta 1937 November-1956 August (Box 141)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Philadelphia Company for Guaranteeing Mortgages 1936 November-1937 August (Box 141)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Philippines, General 1932 November-1933 April, 2 folders (Box 142)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Philippines Government 1945 May-1946 January (Box 142)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Philippine Islands Processing Tax Fund 1936 November-1937 January (Box 142)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Alfred N. Phillips, Jr. 1934 September-1945 January, 2 folders (Box 142)
  - Attorney General Personal File - William Phillips 1936 July-August (Box 142)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Photographs, Lists of 1933 March-1939 January (Box 142)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Picketing 1937 July-August (Box 142)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings re: Terrence N. Pickett 1936 December-1956 May (Box 143)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Congressman Walter M.Pierce 1935 August-1937 June (Box 143)
  - Attorney General Personal File - David A. Pine 1938 February-1941 February (Box 143)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Senator Key Pittman 1933 October-1938 September (Box 143)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Poems n.d. (Box 143)
  - Attorney General Personal File - J.B. Poindexter (Governor of Hawaii) 1935 November-1939 February (Box 143)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Police Commission of St. Paul, Minnesota 1936 September (Box 143)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Political Affairs 1950 July-December (Box 143)
  - Political Contributions 1952-1955 (Box 143)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Political Contributions, Solicitation of 1936 January (Box 143)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Political Observations 1935 August (Box 143)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Power of Attorney General to render opinions n.d. (Box 143)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Presidential Oath (Memo) 1937 January-February (Box 143)
  - Attorney General Personal File - President's Birthday Ball 1940 January-February (Box 143)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - President's visit to Connecticut 1936 September-October (Box 143)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Press and Political Leadership (Essay by Irving Brant) 1938 November (Box 143)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Prisoners, Deportation of Aliens 1933 June-October (Box 143)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Prisons, Bureau of 1935 June-1937 December (Box 143)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Police Training School 1935 October-1936 July (Box 144)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Nathan Popkin 1953 December-1956 May (Box 144)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Prison Industries Reorganization Administration 1936 June-1937 February (Box 144)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Prison Labor 1933 July-September (Box 144)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Prisons, New - P.W.A. Allotment 1938 May-October (Box 144)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Probation Officers 1936 December (Box 144)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Albert N. Prothroe 1933 June-1936 July (Box 144)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Puerto Rican Judiciary 1937 August-1938 May (Box 144)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Puero Rican Vote 1936 October (Box 144)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings re: Puerto Rico, Conditions in 1934 October-1935 May (Box 144)
  - Attorney General Personal File - John L. Purcell 1934 May-1937 February (Box 144)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Pyramid Lake Cases 1937 November-1938 February (Box 144)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - General "Q" 1936 August-1956 (Box 144)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Patrick H. Quinn 1934 June-1950 May (Box 144)
  - Attorney General Personal File - T.D. Quinn 1937 November-1954 August (Box 144)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Quo Warranto Proceedings 1937 September-October (Box 144)